Rādhā-ruchi-ruchavṛtam guru-rūpa harim gauram:
Radha-ruchi-ruchavṛtam guru-rūpa harim gauram.
when Kṛṣṇa takes the guru-rūpa, the form of guru,
Quando Kṛṣṇa prende la guru-rūpa, la forma di guru,
Rādhā-ruchi—He becomes Gaurāṅga.
Rādhā-ruchi: Egli diventa Gaurāṅga.
[Heart and Halo]
[Cuore e Aura]
It’s Kṛṣṇa enveloped, under the influence,
È Kṛṣṇa avviluppato, sotto l'influenza
of the heart and halo of Śrīmati Rādhārāṇī.
del cuore e dell'aura di Śrīmati Rādhārāṇī.
Then, sva-bhaktebhyaḥ śuddhasṁ nija-bhajana-mudrām upadiśan; [Chaitanyastakam 1.1]
Sva-bhaktebhyaḥ śuddhasṁ nija-bhajana-mudrām upadiśan; [Chaitanyastakam 1.1]
then He’s teaching what is Kṛṣṇa consciousness.
dunque sta insegnando cos'è la Coscienza di Kṛṣṇa
It’s very interesting
È molto interessante,
because we take it that guru is the functioning principle
perché presumiamo che il guru sia il principio funzionale
of Divinity revealing Himself,
della divinità che rivela Sé stessa,
but when He wants to teach devotion,
ma quando vuole insegnare la devozione,
He takes the position of Mahāprabhu;
Egli assume il ruolo di Mahāprabhu;
has to be under the influence of Śrīmati Rādhārāṇī
deve sottostare all'influenza di Śrīmati Rādhārāṇī
to give a full, proper conception of Kṛṣṇa,
per dare una piena e corretta concezione di Kṛṣṇa,
a devotional conception of Kṛṣṇa.
una concezione devozionale di Kṛṣṇa.
This is why Mahāprabhu descended into the world—
È per questo che Mahāprabhu discende nel mondo,
to broadcast the glories of Rādhārāṇī.
per diffondere le glorie di Rādhārāṇī.
Everyone already knows so much about Kṛṣṇa,
Tutti già sanno molto di Kṛṣṇa,
or thinks they do.
o pensano di saperlo.
But He’s come to broadcast the greatness of Śrī Rādhā mahimā—
Ma Egli è venuto per diffondere la grandezza di Śrī Rādhāra mahimā—
Her glories; prema-rasa-sīmā—
le Sue glorie, prema-rasa-sīmā,
and what is the highest type of Kṛṣṇa-prema. That He wants to be known.
e qual è il tipo più elevato di Kṛṣṇa-prema, è quello che Egli vuole si conosca.
Kṛṣṇa descends as Mahāprabhu to reveal that in the world.
Kṛṣṇa discende come Mahāprabhu per rivelare questo al mondo.
And to bring others in connection with that divine substance.
E per portare gli altri in connessione con quella sostanza divina.
anarpita-charīṁ chirāt karuṇayāvatīrṇaḥ kalau
Anarpita-charīṁ chirāt karuṇayāvatīrṇaḥ kalau
samarpayitum unnatojjvala-rasāṁ sva-bhakti-śriyam [CС: Ādi, 1.4]
samarpayitum unnatojjvala-rasāṁ sva-bhakti-śriyam [CС: Ādi, 1.4]